<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<collection id="17" available="">
  <item id="107" available="yes">General Health Sciences<description>Access to scientific and technical literature bibliographic national and international databases allowing access to the full documents available online or through the Cooperative Service for Accessing Documents.     </description><portal>                                                                                                           </portal><meta-search/><item id="87" available="yes" href="http://lilacs.bvsalud.org/en/">LILACS - Latin American and Caribbean Health Sciences<description>Latin American and Caribbean Literature on the Health Sciences is a BIREME System's cooperative database which covers literature related to the health sciences and has been published in countries of the Region since 1982. It contains articles from about 670 of the most well-known journals in the medicine field, reaching approximately more than 150,000 records and other documents, such as: theses, chapters of theses, books, chapters of books, congress and conference proceedings, technical and scientific reports and governmental publications.                            </description><portal>                                                                                                                       </portal><meta-search base-search-url="http://bases.bireme.br/cgi-bin/wxislind.exe/iah/online/?IsisScript=iah/iah.xis&amp;base=LILACS&amp;lang=i&amp;nextAction=xml&amp;count=1" search-parameters="exprSearch=" base-browse-url="http://bases.bireme.br/cgi-bin/wxislind.exe/iah/online/?IsisScript=iah/iah.xis&amp;base=LILACS&amp;lang=i&amp;nextAction=lnk"/></item><item id="88" available="yes" href="http://bases.bireme.br/cgi-bin/wxislind.exe/iah/online/?IsisScript=iah/iah.xis&amp;base=MEDLINE&amp;lang=i">MEDLINE - International Database for Medical Literature<description>Database of international literature, by National Library of Medicine - NLM, which gathers bibliographic references and summaries of more than 4000 biomedical journals published in the United States and in other 70 countries. There are approximately 11 million records on biomedical literature since 1966 which cover medicine, nursing, odontology, veterinary and preclinical sciences. Updating is done on a monthly basis. MEDLINE is divided into sections by date.                                                                                                    </description><portal>                                                                                                                  </portal><meta-search base-search-url="http://bases.bireme.br/cgi-bin/wxislind.exe/iah/online/?IsisScript=iah/iah.xis&amp;base=MEDLINE&amp;lang=i&amp;nextAction=xml&amp;count=1" search-parameters="exprSearch=" base-browse-url="http://bases.bireme.br/cgi-bin/wxislind.exe/iah/online/?IsisScript=iah/iah.xis&amp;base=MEDLINE&amp;lang=i&amp;nextAction=lnk"/></item><item id="89" available="yes" href="http://cochrane.bireme.br/portal/php/index.php?lang=en">Cochrane Library<description>The Cochrane Library consists of a collection of updated information sources on evidence-based medicine, including the Cochrane Systematic Reviews database - containing systematic reviews prepared by the Cochrane Collaboration Groups. The access to the Cochrane Library via the VHL is available to the Latin America and Caribbean countries exclusively.                        </description><portal>                                                                                                                    </portal><meta-search base-search-url="http://cochrane.bireme.br/webservices/?service=search&amp;count=1" search-parameters="expression=" base-browse-url="http://cochrane.bireme.br/webservices/?service=search&amp;output=html&amp;lang=en"/></item><item id="72" available="yes" href="http://www.scielo.org/php/index.php?lang=en">SciELO - Scientific Electronic Library Online<description>&lt;span class='corpo'&gt;SciELO - Scientific Electronic Library Online is a model for cooperative electronic publishing of scientific journals on the Internet. Especially conceived to meet the scientific communication needs of developing countries, particularly Latin America and the Caribbean countries, it provides an efficient way to assure universal visibility and accessibility to their scientific literature, contributing to overcome the phenomena known as &amp;quot;lost science&amp;quot;.&lt;/span&gt;                                                                                               </description><portal>                                                                                                                      </portal><meta-search base-search-url="http://www.scielo.br/cgi-bin/wxis.exe/iah/?IsisScript=iah/iah.xis&amp;nextAction=xml&amp;base=article^dlibrary&amp;count=1&amp;lang=i&amp;fmt=citation" search-parameters="exprSearch=" base-browse-url="http://www.scielo.br/cgi-bin/wxis.exe/iah/?IsisScript=iah/iah.xis&amp;nextAction=lnk&amp;base=article^dlibrary&amp;lang=i"/></item></item>
  <item id="108" available="yes">Specialized Areas<description>Access to specialized and thematics bibliographic databases operated in the VHL of Scientific and Technical production about health of the countries of Latin America and the Caribbean. With reference to any type of document: periodicals, magazine articles, books, theses, papers presented at scientific meetings, technical and scientific reports, projects and non-conventional documents.                    </description><portal>                                                                                                          </portal><meta-search/><item id="97" available="yes" href="http://basehisa.coc.fiocruz.br/cgi-bin/wxis.exe/?IsisScript=iah/iah.xic&amp;lang=i&amp;base=HISA">HISA - Latin American and Caribbean History of Public Heatlh<description>HISA - History of the Health - is a bibliographic database developed by the Library of the Oswaldo Cruz House (COC). HISA includes subjects about history of medicine and public health, including events and historical processes in the Human Sciences narratives. HISA's emphasis is on Latin America and the Caribbean.                         </description><portal>                                                                                                                  </portal><meta-search/></item><item id="99" available="yes" href="http://bases.bireme.br/cgi-bin/wxislind.exe/iah/online/?IsisScript=iah/iah.xis&amp;base=LEYES&amp;lang=i">LEYES - Latin American and Caribbean Basic Health Legislation<description>LEYES - Latin American and Caribbean Basic Health Legislation (13/09/2005). The information contained in LEYES data base was extracted mostly from the registers of the 'Index to Latin American Lagislation' by Hispanic Law Division of the Library of Congress of the United States of America, with exception of constitutional provision and health codes.                                                                                          </description><portal>                                                                                                               </portal><meta-search base-search-url="http://bases.bireme.br/cgi-bin/wxislind.exe/iah/online/?IsisScript=iah/iah.xis&amp;base=LEYES&amp;lang=i&amp;nextAction=xml&amp;count=1" search-parameters="exprSearch=" base-browse-url="http://bases.bireme.br/cgi-bin/wxislind.exe/iah/online/?IsisScript=iah/iah.xis&amp;base=LEYES&amp;lang=i&amp;nextAction=xml&amp;count=1"/></item><item id="100" available="yes" href="http://bases.bireme.br/cgi-bin/wxislind.exe/iah/online/?IsisScript=iah/iah.xis&amp;base=MedCarib&amp;lang=i">MEDCARIB - Caribbean Health Sciences Literature<description>Bibliographic database which gathers the literature in health sciences which comes, most of the time, from Caribbean English speaking countries. It is produced by Caribbean Net and coordinated by MedCarib Net Coordinating Center, Medical Library, University of West Indies, Mona, Kingston - Jamaica. It indexes all types of documents, such as books, chapters of books, theses, technical reports, congress and conference proceedings, and articles from journals. It contains references of documents dating from the 18th Century up to the present date.                                                                                          </description><portal>                                                                                                              </portal><meta-search base-search-url="http://bases.bireme.br/cgi-bin/wxislind.exe/iah/online/?IsisScript=iah/iah.xis&amp;base=MedCarib&amp;lang=i&amp;nextAction=xml&amp;count=1" search-parameters="exprSearch=" base-browse-url="http://bases.bireme.br/cgi-bin/wxislind.exe/iah/online/?IsisScript=iah/iah.xis&amp;base=MedCarib&amp;lang=i&amp;nextAction=lnk"/></item></item>
  <item id="109" available="yes">International Agencies<description>Access to databases coordinated by the Libraries of Pan American Health Organization (PAHO) and World Health Organization (WHO), operated within the VHL that contains bibliographic references, abstracts, periodicals articles, among other documents in the health field. Available in Portuguese, Spanish and English.                   </description><portal>                                                                                                               </portal><meta-search/><item id="102" available="yes" href="http://bases.bireme.br/cgi-bin/wxislind.exe/iah/online/?IsisScript=iah/iah.xis&amp;base=PAHO&amp;lang=i">PAHO - PAHO HQ Library Catalog<description>It is a database that contains bibliographic references and abstracts from collection of the Pan American Health Organization (PAHO) headquarters Library. It includes the documentation on health subjects indexed by PAHO Library in Washington. The PAHO database is a reference source on the production activities of the Organization and includes Latin America and Caribbean health topics.                                                                                      </description><portal>                                                                                                              </portal><meta-search base-search-url="http://bases.bireme.br/cgi-bin/wxislind.exe/iah/online/?IsisScript=iah/iah.xis&amp;base=PAHO&amp;lang=i&amp;nextAction=xml&amp;count=1" search-parameters="exprSearch=" base-browse-url="http://bases.bireme.br/cgi-bin/wxislind.exe/iah/online/?IsisScript=iah/iah.xis&amp;base=PAHO&amp;lang=i&amp;nextAction=lnk"/></item><item id="103" available="yes" href="http://bases.bireme.br/cgi-bin/wxislind.exe/iah/online/?IsisScript=iah/iah.xis&amp;base=WHOLIS&amp;lang=i">WHOLIS - World Health Organization Library Information System<description>WHOLIS is a bibliographic database that contains publications from the World Health Organization (WHO) and from its Regional Representative Offices. It indexes journal articles, technical and political documents and publications where WHO collaborates to other editors and international organizations.                         </description><portal>                                                                                                             </portal><meta-search base-search-url="http://bases.bireme.br/cgi-bin/wxislind.exe/iah/online/?IsisScript=iah/iah.xis&amp;base=WHOLIS&amp;lang=i&amp;nextAction=xml&amp;count=1" search-parameters="exprSearch=" base-browse-url="http://bases.bireme.br/cgi-bin/wxislind.exe/iah/online/?IsisScript=iah/iah.xis&amp;base=WHOLIS&amp;lang=i&amp;nextAction=lnk"/></item></item>
  <item id="117" available="yes" href="http://evidences.bvsalud.org/php/index.php?lang=en">Evidence Portal<description>The Evidence Portal of the Virtual Health Library (VHL) unites, organizes, and offers integrated access to health information sources of  better level of evidence in agreement with the Evidence-based Medicine (EBM) methodology, and access to information sources about the EBM methodology itself. It has as aim to promote the use of the information of better level of evidence to support the decision-making processes in health care and management, as well as to the process of development of new evidence-based studies and application of the EBM methodology.                                 </description><portal>                                                 </portal><meta-search base-search-url="http://search.bvsalud.org/evidences/?output=metasearch&amp;lang=en" search-parameters="q=" base-browse-url="http://search.bvsalud.org/evidences/?output=html&amp;lang=en"/></item>
  <item id="116" available="yes" href="http://portal.campusvirtualsp.org/virtualcampus/drupal/index.php?q=en">Virtual Campus of Public Health<description>Decentralized network of individuals, institutions and organizations that shares  courses, resources, services and education activities. The common objective is  improve the subject in Public Health. Virtual Campus of Public Health makes an extensive use of new technologies and networks of health education and aims to become a space for creativity and innovation in developing policies and procedures for continuing health education.            </description><portal>                                                     </portal><meta-search base-search-url="http://search.bvsalud.org/cvsp/?output=metasearch&amp;lang=en" search-parameters="q=" base-browse-url="http://search.bvsalud.org/cvsp/?output=html&amp;lang=en"/></item>
  <item id="114" available="yes" href="http://lis.bvs.br/lis-Regional/xmlListT.php?x=0&amp;xml[]=@/I/define.xml&amp;xsl=http://lis.bvs.br/lis-Regional/home.xsl">HIL- Health Information Locator<description>LIS - Health Information Locator is a catalog of relevant health sites, selected according to quality criteria. The content is constituted by metadata that describes information sources available in the internet, pointing to the hypertext links. LIS applies a methodology based on the Dublin Core and GILS formats (Global Information Locator Service).                                                 </description><portal>                                                 </portal><meta-search base-search-url="http://lis.bvs.br/webservices/index.php?service=search&amp;count=1" search-parameters="expression=" base-browse-url="http://lis.bvs.br/webservices/index.php?service=search&amp;output=html"/></item>
  <item id="118" available="yes">Health Terminology<description>The health Terminology aims to improve and standardize terms, concepts and acronyms used by BIREME and related entities, promoting recuperation, access, disclosure and dissemination of knowledge and health information.                      </description><portal>                                 </portal><meta-search/><item id="113" available="yes" href="http://decs.bvs.br/I/homepagei.htm" img="http://h1n1.influenza.bvsalud.org/local//decs.gif">DeCS- Health Sciences Descriptors<description>DeCS is a controlled vocabulary for Health Sciences, developed from MeSH - Medical Subject Headings of the U.S. National Library of Medicine (NLM) with the purpose of permitting the use of common terminology for searching in three languages, providing a consistent and unique environment for retrieval of information regardless of the language.                                   </description><portal>                                                   </portal><meta-search/></item></item>
  <item id="112" available="yes">Document Access<description>Provides access to documents in the area of health sciences.                              </description><portal>                                                        </portal><meta-search/><item id="110" available="yes" href="http://scad.bvs.br/php/index.php?lang=en" img="http://regional.bvsalud.org/image/common/logo_scad.gif">SCAD- Cooperative Service for Accessing Documents<description>SCAD - Virtual Health Library's Cooperative Service for Accessing Documents provides efficient document delivery service among libraries and users in the Latin American and Caribbean Region.                         </description><portal>                                                          </portal><meta-search/></item><item id="111" available="yes" href="http://portal.revistas.bvs.br/main.php?home=true&amp;lang=en">Portal of Scientific Journals<description>The Portal of scientific journals provides information about bibliographic description of titles of scientific journals in the field of health, allows access to the electronic format and libraries collections that cooperate with the Collective Catalog SeCS - Health Sciences Series. There are more than 13 000 records of national and international journals indexed on main bibliographic index of health.              </description><portal>                                                           </portal><meta-search base-search-url="http://portal.revistas.bvs.br/webservices/?service=search&amp;count=1" search-parameters="expression=" base-browse-url="http://portal.revistas.bvs.br/webservices/?service=search&amp;output=html&amp;lang=en"/></item></item>
</collection>
