<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<about id="19" available="">
  <item id="8" available="yes">About VHL<description>This area shows the history about this VHL and its objectives, as well as creation date, leaders, development plan, matrix of responsibilities, meeting minutes and access statistics.   </description><portal><p>The Virtual Health Library (VHL) was launched in March 1998, with the Declaration of San José Towards the Virtual Health Library, approved during the 4th Regional Congress on Health Sciences Information (CRICS4).</p> <p>In this Declaration the country representatives recognize that the access to information constitutes one of the central elements to reach equity in health adapting them to the reality of the region.</p> <p>Based on these premises, they made the commitment to cooperatively built the Virtual Health Library, in order to strengthen capabilities and infrastructures and to facilitate the broad access to the information for the permanent improvement of the health and for sustainable human development of the region.</p> <p>According to the VHL’s model, the network of information producers, intermediaries and users progressively moves towards the operation of products and services in a shared space in the Internet. In this shared space, the VHL progressively forms dynamic networks of information flows and sources, created and operated in a cooperative and decentralized manner with explicit quality control.</p> <p>The VHL is, therefore, a public space of interaction between producers, intermediaries and users, thus contributing for the publication, record, organization, indexation, preservation, quality control, and integrity as well as for visibility, access and use of the information generated by national research, teaching and health care systems.</p> </portal></item>
  <item id="3" available="yes">Consultative Committee<description>Consisting of representative members of institutions in an equitative mode, its function is to elaborate work plans that determine the main lines of action of the VHL and the selection of the quality criteria of the information sources and its social network promotion. Among the Consultive Committee attributions is the strategic decision-making for the continuos evaluation and development of the VHL.         </description><portal><p>VHL operation is guided by an Consultative Committee composed of the following institutions:</p> <ul>     <li>Institution A</li>     <li>Institution B</li>     <li>Institution C</li> </ul> <p>The <strong>Executive Secretariat </strong>of VHL is represented by the institution X, which has  political condition, economic, technological and human resources favorable to assume leadership in the operation of the VHL instance, and is responsible for monitoring the actions deliberate by the Consultative Committee, expressed in its project and plans of action, principally the promotion of cooperative job in networking of operation of information sources. </p> <p>Is the responsibility of the executive secretariat to promote the effective functioning of the Consultative Committee, including the organization of periodic meetings and remote presence.</p>                           </portal></item>
  <item id="4" available="yes">Meeting Minutes<description>It's a register from Consultative Committee with its meetings and activities.                              </description><portal>                                 </portal><item id="6" available="yes">I Consultative Committee Meeting<description>Brazil, December 01 st, 2010                       </description><portal>                        </portal></item><item id="7" available="yes">II Consultative Committee Meeting<description>Brazil, January 01 st, 2011                     </description><portal>                     </portal></item></item>
  <item id="1" available="yes" href="http://bvsmodelo.bvsalud.org/php/index.php?lang=en">About VHL Model<description>It contains the Virtual Health Library's methodologies and applications.                                                        </description><portal>                                                               </portal></item>
  <item id="2" available="yes">Access Statistics<description>It is a counter of access for visit metrics on VHL.     </description><portal>     </portal></item>
</about>
