<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<collection id="31" available="">
  <item id="2" available="yes" href="http://diretorios.bvs.br/direve/?lang=en" img="http://h1n1.influenza.bvsalud.org/local//eventos.gif">Events Directory<description>Directory that makes available data on scientific events in the health area such as: congresses, seminars, conferences, etc. It primarily records events that take place in Latin America and Caribbean.                                        </description><portal>                                                   </portal><meta-search base-search-url="http://diretorios.bvs.br/webservices/?service=search&amp;count=1" search-parameters="expression=" base-browse-url="http://diretorios.bvs.br/webservices/?service=search&amp;lang=en&amp;output=html"/></item>
  <item id="1" available="yes" href="http://centros.bvsalud.org/?lang=en" img="http://h1n1.influenza.bvsalud.org/local//logobvs2.jpg">VHL Network Directory<description>Directory that makes available data on the VHL Network libraries. It includes information on libraries and documentation centers from Latin American and Caribbean national networks, specialized areas of Brazilian Network on Information Health Sciences and institution libraries that use the VHL.        </description><portal>                                                    </portal><meta-search/></item>
  <item id="3" available="yes" href="http://regional.bvsalud.org/php/level.php?lang=en&amp;component=109&amp;item=14" img="http://h1n1.influenza.bvsalud.org/local/agt_family.jpg">Virtual Communities / Online Collaborative Spaces<description>The Virtual Communities or Online Collaborative Spaces, in VHL, promote and facilitate the utilization of formal communication channels by specific groups, which register, make possible the recovery, and expand the dissemination of his ideas and knowledge. Integrated in VHL, in the current paradigm of participation in the Web, the opportunities for collaboration make viable the inclusion of the general knowledge in its areas of news, documents, images, forums, chats, and blogs, characteristics of that source of information, and are being increasingly used in the sharing of relevant information on specific subjects.                                                 </description><portal>                                                 </portal><meta-search/></item>
</collection>
